Talab Hussein

Dubai, United Arab Emirates 055-569-7370 | <u>Talab.Hussein@asu.edu</u>

SUMMARY

Western educated software engineer with more than three years of work experience in companies and research institutes located in the United States. Specialized in data science and analytics, software development and algorithms, software testing, and product quality assurance.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

August 2013 - December 2017

Ira A. Fulton Schools of Engineering - Arizona State University, USA

Primary Focus: Data Science & Analytics Secondary Focus: Information Security

• **GPA:** 3.01 / 4.00

• Awards: Dean's List for Spring 2016 & 2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Skills: Java, C++, C#, JavaScript, Python, SQL, R

Software Tools: Tableau, Matlab, R Studio, Microsoft Excel, Power BI, Eclipse Concepts: Data Analytics, Business Analytics, Data Visualization, Data Mining Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Node, React, Angular, JQuery, D3, Bootstrap

Languages: Arabic (Native), English (Fluent)

WORK EXPERIENCE

NextGen Aeronautics

Los Angeles, California, USA

May 2017 – July 2017

Software Engineer, R&D
Built a cross-platform desktop application using C++ that runs on various platforms.

- Developed and designed the responsive graphical user interface (presentation layer).
- Collaborated with the mechanical and hardware engineers to update the product in real-time.
- Re-engineered the pre-existing code base and configured it to function on any Android device.

Sheikh Zayed Institute for Pediatric Surgical Innovation

Washington, D.C., USA

Undergraduate Lab Assistant

January 2017 - May 2017

- Imported, cleaned, analyzed, validated, and modeled patients data with the purpose of making conclusions from the data for decision-making purposes and revealing ways to improve the organization.
- Researched clinical trials and utilized pain reported outcome tools for pain management and reporting.
- Enhanced communication between clinicians and patients by building a mobile app to report pain outcomes.

University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA

Software Engineer Mentor

March 2017

- Answered questions from any team participating in the hackathon and help guide them resolve technical issues.
- Assisted teams on a wide variety of tasks, from idea brainstorming to project release management.

Naffco Dubai, UAE

Software Engineer Intern

May 2016 – *July* 2016

- Performed functional, regression, and integration testing on Oracle CRM system and reported bugs to the team.
- Developed test plans and test cases for the functional areas to be tested and documented the same.
- Executed the test cases, entered defects in the bug tracking system and followed-up on defects with the development team in an agile environment.

ASU Technology Studio

Tempe, Arizona, USA

- Maintained the pre-existing website and built new features based on the requirements.
- Developed technical skills rapidly by interacting with different teams and divisions.